A Guide to Project Files of the Virginia Code Commission, 1970-2013.
Library of Virginia
Library of Virginia
Project Files of the Virginia Code Commission,
1970-2013.
The Library of Virginia
53908
Virginia Code Commission
3 cu. ft.
Unprocessed.
These records are part of the Virginia Code Commission record group (RG# 82)
Acquisition Information
Accession 53908 was transferred by the Virginia Code Commission on May 17, 2023
Virginia Code Commission
Virginia. -- Administrative Process Act.
Administrative agencies -- Virginia.
Administrative law -- Virginia.
Administrative procedure -- Virginia.
Delegated legislation -- Virginia.
Laws -- Virginia.
Statutes -- Virginia.
Virginia Administrative Code
Codes (regulations) -- aat.
Drafts (documents) -- aat.
Forms. -- aat.
Letters (correspondence) -- aat.
State government records -- Virginia. -- aat.
Virginia register of regulations. -- Periodicals
Historical Information
The Commission on Code Recodification was created by an act of the General Assembly passed on March 30, 1946. Its principal duty was to make a complete recodification of the statute laws of the state of a general nature. This task was completed two years later, and the new code was approved by the General Assembly on March 30, 1948. An act passed by the General Assembly on March 16, 1948, made the commission a permanent agency of the legislative branch of government and changed the name of the commission to the Virginia Code Commission. The commission supervises the codification of the statutes after each General Assembly session and revises and recodifies portions of the Code of Virginia as needed.
In 1992 the Commission was charged with the responsibility of creating Virginia's first administrative code of regulations by compiling and codifying all of the administrative regulations of state agencies. The Commission also oversees the bi-weekly publication of The Virginia Register of Regulations, which is used by state agencies during the adoption of new regulations to be included in the Administrative Process Act.
Project files, 1970-2013, of the Virginia Code Commission include records related to the Obsolete Provision Project / Repeal Project, as well as records of the Virginia Register Advisory Committee and the Administrative Law Advisory Committee. Includes correspondence, code citations, legislation, research materials, and reports.
Contents List
- Project files, 1970-2013.
  - Obsolete Provision Project / Repeal Project, 1970-2013.
    - Authorities, 1999, undated. (Box 1)
    - Boards, 2000. (Box 1)
    - Category 3,. (Box 1)
    - Category 6, undated. (Box 1)
    - Category 7, undated. (Box 1)
    - Charters, 1999. (Box 1)
    - Chesterfield County Toll Road Authority, 2000. (Box 1)
    - Code Provisions for 2000 Repeal, 2000. (Box 1)
    - Codification question, undated. (Box 1)
    - Commissions, undated. (Box 1)
    - Councils, 2000. (Box 1)
    - Effect of omission of 1906 act from 1919 code, 1998. (Box 1)
    - Folio views, undated. (Box 1)
    - Game and Inland Fisheries, Dept. of, 2000. (Box 1)
    - German and Belgian Shepherds, undated. (Box 1)
    - Hunting deer with rifles in certain counties, undated. (Box 1)
    - Hunting in Buckingham County, undated. (Box 1)
    - Legislation - Acts, 1970. (Box 1)
    - Legislation - General / Specific, 2000. (Box 1)
    - Legislative history and secondary sources, undated. (Box 1)
    - Miscellaneous, undated. (Box 1)
    - Miscellaneous - Materials, undated. (Box 1)
    - Miscellaneous - State information, 2000. (Box 1)
    - Notes, 2000. (Box 1)
    - Presentations, publications and memos, 1993-2000. (Box 1)
    - Private investigation, undated. (Box 1)
    - Recommendations, 2000-2004. (Box 1)
    - Repeal of obsolete statutes and acts of assembly - Assignment and plan, 2000. (Box 1)
    - Repeal Project, 2003. (Box 1)
    - Repeal Project, 2004. (Box 1)
    - Repeal Project, 2005. (Box 1)
    - Repeal Project, 2006. (Box 1)
    - Repeal Project, 2007. (Box 1)
    - Repeal Project, 2008. (Box 1)
    - Repeal Project, 2009. (Box 1)
    - Repeal Project, 2011. (Box 1)
    - Repeal Project, 2012. (Box 1)
    - Repeal Project, 2013. (Box 1)
    - Repeals, 2003. (Box 1)
    - Report of the Commission on Code Recodification, 1948. (Box 1)
    - Research, 2000-2001. (Box 1)
    - Research - Acts, 1970-1979. (Box 1)
    - Research - Acts, undated. (Box 1)
    - Research - Case law and statutes, undated. (Box 1)
    - Supreme Court Law Library, undated. (Box 1)
    - Title revision, undated. (Box 1)
  - Virginia Register Advisory Committee, 1974-1986.
    - Correspondence and reports, 1974. (Box 2)
    - Correspondence and reports, 1974-1979. (Box 2)
    - Correspondence and reports, 1976-1982. (Box 2)
    - Correspondence and reports, 1985-1986. (Box 2)
  - Administrative Law Advisory Committee, 1985-1999.
    - Correspondence and reports, 1985-1999. (Box 3)